Guide to the Bruce J. Zobel Papers, 1937-2008 MC 00259
Special Collections Research Center
Bruce J. Zobel Papers
1937-2008 and undated
MC 00259
Special Collections Research Center
193.5 Linear feet
The Bruce J. Zobel Papers contain diaries, correspondence, speeches, an autobiography, articles, awards, reports, course information, theses proposals, serials, conference and symposia information, research plans, photographs, slides, artifacts, and other materials related to Zobel's career in forestry. Included are materials relating to Zobel's work on the faculty of North Carolina State University as well as work with the Central America and Mexico Resources Cooperative (CAMCORE), the Cooperative Forest Genetics Research Program, the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, the Marcus Wallenberg Foundation for Promoting Scientific Research in the Forest Industry, the N.C. State-Industry Cooperative Forest Tree Improvement Program, the Southern Forest Tree Improvement Committee, the Technical Association of the Pulp and Paper Industry (TAPPI), Zobel Forestry Associates, and other organizations. Major topics include international forest improvement programs, forest genetics, wood properties, forest management, and tropical forestry.
Bruce J. Zobel, born in 1920, is an internationally respected lecturer, consultant, professor, and expert on forest genetics and forest improvement. His career at North Carolina State University as a professor, head of the North Carolina Tree Improvement Cooperative, and professor emeritus has spanned nearly fifty years, from 1957 to 2004.
386 archival boxes
Zobel, Bruce, 1920-
Restrictions to Access
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, North Carolina State University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
With the exception of student records and a folder of personal information, the collection is open for research. Access requires at least 24 hours advance notice.
Acquisitions Information
Gift of Bruce J. Zobel, 1998 - 2008.
Biographical Note
Bruce John Zobel was born on February 11, 1920, in Los Gatos, California, the youngest of August and Emma Zobel's six children. His parents owned a fruit and vegetable farm in the Pajaro Valley in California near Watsonville. The entire Zobel family helped with farm duties, but education remained a priority for all of the Zobel children. Zobel graduated from high school in 1938.
In 1938, Bruce Zobel and his future wife Barbara both attended Salinas Junior College in preparation to attend the University of California in Berkeley. In 1941, the two married, and moved to Berkeley to attend school. In 1942, their first child, Don, was born. The following year, Bruce graduated with a bachelor's degree and joined the Pacific Lumber Company as a logging engineer. He remained in this position until 1944, when he was drafted into the U.S. Marine Corps. In 1945, the Zobels' second child, Kathy, was born.
During his time with the Marines, Zobel worked at Camp Lejeune and helped develop a forestry management program. In 1946, Zobel applied for permanent separation from the Marine Corps and returned home to California to attend graduate school at Berkeley, making use of G.I. Bill benefits. During the time that Zobel pursued a masters and Ph.D. degree, he worked as a Senior Laboratory Assistant in the Forestry School
After receiving both degrees, the Zobels moved to College Station, Texas in 1951 where Bruce took a job with Texas A&M University, the Texas Forest Service, and the Texas Agricultural Experiment Station. He worked as on a tree improvement program for all three employers. In 1952, the Zobel's adopted Lois Jean, their second daughter. Two years later, Julia Ann, another daughter, was adopted.
His achievements attracted the attention of North Carolina State College (later North Carolina State University) in 1956, and the Zobels moved to the Raleigh area to work for the Tree Improvement Cooperative. In addition to running the cooperative, Zobel taught courses and advised forestry students. He became a respected authority on forest improvement and forest genetics, and was honored with a number of awards (see chronology).
During his career with North Carolina State University (NCSU), Zobel traveled extensively. These trips offered him the opportunity to meet potential clients for consulting work. In 1979, Zobel retired from NCSU, although he continued to teach part-time as a Professor Emeritus until 2002. Zobel independently consulted for international firms over the next few years, and in 1984, he founded the Zobel Forestry Associates. Zobel served as president and William Ladrach served as general manager. In 1995, Zobel sold his half of the company to Ladrach, but continued to work as an associate.
Chronology of Events in Bruce J. Zobel's Life
February 11, 1920 Bruce J. Zobel born in California to August John and Emma Zobel
June 21, 1941 Married Barbara June Lemon in Carson City, Nevada
1943 Received B.S. in Forestry, University of California, Berkeley
1943-1944 Worked as Assistant to Logging Engr., Pacific Lumber Co., California
1945-1946 Worked as Forestry Officer, United States Marine Corps, Camp LeJeune, North Carolina
1947-1948 Worked as Senior Lab Assistant, University of California
1949 Received Master's in Forestry, University of California, Berkeley
1951 Received Ph.D. in Forestry, University of California, Berkeley
1951-1957 Worked as Silviculturalist, Texas A&M University
1956-1979 Served as Director of Industrial Forest Tree Improvement and Hardwood Programs
1957 Named Associate Professor, North Carolina State University (NCSU)
1960 Named Professor of Forest Genetics, NCSU
1961 Named E. F. Conger Distinguished Professor of Forestry, NCSU
1965 Received Governor's Award for Conservation, North Carolina
1965 Received Award of Merit, Society of Gamma Sigma Delta
1968 Received Barrington Moore Memorial Award (Biological Research), Society of American Foresters
1968 Named Fellow, International Academy of Wood Sciences
1969 Named Fellow, Society of American Foresters
1972 Received O. Max Gardener Award, University of North Carolina (System)
1973 Named TAPPI Fellow, Technical Association of the Pulp and Paper Industry
1973 Received Outstanding Extension Services Award, North Carolina State University
1974 Received Achievement Award, Appalachian Section of the Society of American Foresters
1974 Received the TAPPI Gold Medal, Technical Association of the Pulp and Paper Industry
1975 Joined the Swedish Academy of Agriculture and Silviculture
1976 Received the Bicentennial Award, North Carolina Forestry Association
1979 Received Certificate of Appreciation, American Forestry Association
1979 Became Professor Emeritus
1980 Received International Gamma Sigma Delta Award
1982 Named Man of the Year, North Carolina Forestry Association
1983 Served as Honorary Chairman, CAMCORE (International) Cooperative
1983 Joined Socio Honorario, Association Argentina de Estudios Forestales
1984-1989 Served as member of the Selection Committee for the Marcus Wallenberg Foundation in Sweden
1985 Received Bernard Fernow Award in International Forestry, American Forestry Association
1986 Received Honorary D.Sc., Syracuse University
1986-1995 Served as President of Zobel Forestry Associates, Inc.
1988 Received Sir William Schlict Memorial Medal, Society of American Foresters
1990 Received Top in Efficiency Award, Pizano Company, Colombia
1994 Received the Integer Award, 2nd International Agribusiness Seminar, Monterrey, Mexico for Outstanding Agriculturalist
1995-present Served as Senior Associate, Zobel Forestry Associates
2004 Received Alexander Quarles Holladay Medal for Excellence, North Carolina State University
Scope and Content Note
The Bruce J. Zobel Papers includes diaries, correspondence, speeches, an autobiography, articles, awards, reports, course information, theses proposals, serials, conference and symposia information, research plans, photographs, slides, artifacts, and other materials related to Zobel's forestry career. Included are materials relating to Zobel's work on the faculty of North Carolina State University as well as work with the Central America and Mexico Resources Cooperative (CAMCORE), the Cooperative Forest Genetics Research Program, the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, the Marcus Wallenberg Foundation for Promoting Scientific Research in the Forest Industry, the N.C. State-Industry Cooperative Forest Tree Improvement Program, the Southern Forest Tree Improvement Committee, the Technical Association of the Pulp and Paper Industry (TAPPI), Zobel Forestry Associates, and other organizations. Major topics include international forest improvement programs, forest genetics, wood properties, forest management, and tropical forestry.
Organization of Collection
Materials have been kept in their original order as much as possible. Please see the series notes for more information about the arrangement of each series.
The collection is organized into sixteen series:
Series 01. Diaries, consists of daily and travel diaries, organized chronologically and by country of travel.
Series 02. Correspondence, includes correspondence with Gunnar Nicholson and other researchers on forestry topics.
Series 03. Speeches and Presentations, includes speeches and other materials related to the events at which Zobel spoke.
Series 04. Biographical Information includes Zobel's autobiography as well as materials related to his education and awards.
Series 05. Books and Publications contains materials related to the publication of each of Zobel's books, as well as a list of articles written by Zobel, some of which are organized into this series.
Series 06. Professional Activities, includes materials related to the various organizations that Zobel worked with and for during his career.
Series 07. Education and Teaching, includes course information and student files related to Zobel's teaching career.
Series 08. Forestry Resources, contains a variety of research plans.
Series 09. Serials is comprised of forestry-related serials from around the world.
Series 10. Reports contains reports on forestry issues from various countries and on multiple topics.
Series 11. Conference and Symposia Materials contains materials used in Zobel's forestry research.
Series 12. Photographs and Slides contains images used by Zobel in lectures and courses taught.
Series 13. Scrapbooks, contains two scrapbooks: one is a collection of wildflowers, the other a retirement scrapbook.
Series 14. Artifacts contains plaques, medals, awards, and tributes given to Zobel during his career, as well as some teaching examples of wood and pinecones.
Series 15. Card Index contains index cards citing articles on forestry topics.
Series 16. Reprints contains full-text reprints of some of the articles referenced by the card index in the previous series.
Central America and Mexico Resources Cooperative.; Cooperative Forest Genetics Research Program.; Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations.; Marcus Wallenberg Foundation for Promoting Scientific Research in the Forest Industry.; N.C. State-Industry Cooperative Forest Tree Improvement Program.; Nicholson, Gunnar; North Carolina State University. College of Natural Resources--History.; North Carolina State University. School of Forest Resources--Faculty.; Southern Forest Tree Improvement Committee.; Technical Association of the Pulp and Paper Industry.; Zobel Forestry Associates.; Zobel, Bruce, 1920-; Awards; Books; Card indexes; College teachers--North Carolina--History; Diaries; Forest genetics--Research; Forest management--Research; Forests and forestry--Study and teaching--North Carolina; Letters (correspondence); Photographs; Publications; Rain forests--Research; Scrapbooks; Slides; Speeches; Travelers--Diaries; Trees--Diseases and pests; Trees--Tropics
- Diaries, 1958-2006; MC 00259 Series 01; 4.5 Linear feet; 9 Boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The Diaries series is divided into two main subsections: daily diaries and travel diaries. The daily diaries record daily events and appointments, as well as notes on daily accomplishments and weather conditions. The travel diaries record Bruce and Barbara Zobel's trips throughout the United States and abroad doing forest consulting. Some of these trips were taken to attend the Wallenberg Prize meetings in Sweden, and many others were taken to do forestry work, many while consulting as part of Zobel Forestry Associates. The diaries are mainly arranged according to country; however, some are arranged according to the name of the corporation for whom Zobel consulted. Barbara Zobel prepared most of the diaries, which recorded not only their work but also the social and geographical conditions of the areas they visited.
  In addition to the diaries, the Zobels prepared summaries, which include: (A) General Comments About the Area, (B) Exciting and/or Dangerous Situations, (C) Travel, (D) Social Situations, Including Hospitality, (E) Forest Management and Utilization and Scientific Activities, (F) Governmental Operations and Actions, (G) Visits with Historical Importance, (H) Special People Encountered As Colleagues or Friends, and (I) Special Visits. The summaries for each country immediately follow the corresponding travel diaries.
  Additions were incorporated into this series in 2007.
  - Daily Diaries, 1958-2002
    - Daily Diary, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Daily Diary, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Daily Diary, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Daily Diary, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Daily Diary, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Daily Diary, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Daily Diary, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Daily Diary, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Daily Diary, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Daily Diary, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Daily Diary, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Daily Diary, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Daily Diary, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Daily Diary, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Daily Diary, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Daily Diary, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Daily Diary, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Daily Diary, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Daily Diary, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Daily Diary, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Daily Diary, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Daily Diary, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Daily Diary, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Daily Diary, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Daily Diary, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Daily Diary, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Daily Diary, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Daily Diary, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Daily Diary, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Daily Diary, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Daily Diary, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Daily Diary, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Daily Diary, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Daily Diary, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Daily Diary, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Daily Diary, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Daily Diary, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Daily Diary, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Daily Diary, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Daily Diary, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Daily Diary, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Daily Diary, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Daily Diary, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Daily Diary, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Daily diary, 2003 (Box 386, Folder 1)
    - Daily diary, 2004 (Box 386, Folder 2)
    - Daily diary, 2005 (Box 386, Folder 3)
    - Daily diary, 2006 (Box 386, Folder 4)
    - Daily diary, 2007 (Box 386, Folder 5)
    - Daily diary, 2008 (Box 386, Folder 6)
  - Travel Diaries, 1961-2006
    - Introduction (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - General Introduction, 1996 (Box 375, Folder 1)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition note
      Addition 2007
    - Wallenberg Prize Meetings, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      (Unabridged)
    - Wallenberg Prize Meetings, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Wallenberg Prize Meetings: Summary (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Wallenberg Prize Meetings, Experiences (Box 375, Folder 2)
    - Colombia, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Colombia, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Colombia, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Colombia, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Colombia, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Colombia, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Colombia: Summary (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Colombia: Summary (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Colombia: Summary (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Colombia: Summary (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Colombia: Summary (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Columbia: Experiences, 2002 (Box 375, Folder 3)
    - Venezuela, 1979-1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Venezuela, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Venezuela, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Venezuela, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Venezuela, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Venezuela, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Venezuela, 1997 (Box 375, Folder 4)
    - Venezuela: Summary (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Venezuela: Summary (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Venezuela: Summary (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Venezuela: Summary (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Venezuela: Summary (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Venezuela: Summary (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Venezuela: Summary (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Venezuela: Experiences, 1992 (Box 375, Folder 5)
    - Venezuela: Experiences (Box 375, Folder 6)
    - Brazil, 1964-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Brazil, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Brazil, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Brazil, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Brazil, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Brazil, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Brazil, 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Brazil: Central and Northern (Box 375, Folder 7)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Brazil: Summary (Box 375, Folder 8)
    - Brazil: Experiences (Box 375, Folder 9)
    - Chile, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chile, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chile: Summary (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Chile: Executive Summary, 1978 (Box 375, Folder 10)
    - Chile: Summary (Box 375, Folder 11)
    - Chile: Forestry (Box 375, Folder 12)
    - Chile: Government (Box 375, Folder 13)
    - Mexico, 1981-1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Mexico: Summary (Box 375, Folder 14)
    - South Africa and Rhodesia, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - South Africa and Rhodesia, Summary (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - South Africa: Summary (Box 375, Folder 15)
    - South Africa and Rhodesia: Experiences, 2006 (Box 375, Folder 16)
    - Australia and New Zealand, 1965-1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Australia and New Zealand, Summary (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Australia and New Zealand, Summary (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Australia, New Zealand, and Fiji (Box 375, Folder 17)
    - Canada (Eastern), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Canada (Eastern), 1982-1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Canada (Eastern), 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Canada (Eastern), 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Canada (Eastern), 1994-1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Canada (Eastern), Summary (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Canada (Eastern), Summary (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Canada (Eastern), Summary (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Canada (Eastern), Summary (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Canada (Eastern), Summary (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Canada (Eastern), Summary (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Canada (Eastern), Summary (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Canada (Western), 1975-1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Canada (Western), 1986-1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Canada (Western), 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Canada (Western), Summary (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Canada (Western), Summary (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Canada (Western), Summary (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Indonesia, 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Indonesia, Summary (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Indonesia: Summary (Box 375, Folder 18)
    - Europe, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Europe, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Europe, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Europe, 1966-1980 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Europe, Summary (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Europe, Summary (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Central America, 1978-1994 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Costa Rica, Summary (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Guatemala, Summary (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Mexico and Ecuador, Summary (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - United States (Consulting): Albemarle-Hoerner Waldorf (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - United States (Consulting): American Can (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - United States (Consulting): Blanding Paper Company (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - United States (Consulting): Bowaters (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - United States (Consulting): Brunswick Pulp (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - United States (Consulting): Catawba Timber (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - United States (Consulting): Champion (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - United States (Consulting): Chesapeake (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - United States (Consulting): Colony Timber (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - United States (Consulting): Container (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - United States (Consulting): Continental Can (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - United States (Consulting): Georgia Kraft (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - United States (Consulting): Georgia Pacific (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - United States (Consulting): Great Southern (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - United States (Consulting): Hammermill (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - United States (Consulting): Hardwood Research Council (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - United States (Consulting): Hiwassee Land Company (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - United States (Consulting): International Paper Company (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - United States (Consulting): Kimberly Clark (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - United States (Consulting): MacMillan Bloedel (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - United States (Consulting): Masonite Corporation (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - United States (Consulting): Mead Corporation (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - United States (Consulting): North Carolina Forest Service (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - United States (Consulting): Potlach (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - United States (Consulting): Rayonier (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - United States (Consulting): Riegel (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - United States (Consulting): Scott Paper (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - United States (Consulting): Simpson and Howe (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - United States (Consulting): South Carolina Forest Service (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - United States (Consulting): St. Regis (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - United States (Consulting): Tennessee River (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - United States (Consulting): Union Camp (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - United States (Consulting): Virginia Division of Forestry (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - United States (Consulting): Westvaco (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - United States (Consulting): Weyerhauser (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Trips, 1979-1989 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Trips, 1990-1995 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Trips, Summary (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Trips, Summary (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Trips, Summary (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1956-2006; MC 00259 Series 02; 0.5 Linear feet; 1 Box
  The Correspondence series begins with correspondence between Bruce Zobel and Gunnar Nicholson, the well-known Swedish forester. Much of this correspondence is undated. The rest of the series contains general correspondence. Topics include research, meetings, letters between Zobel and North Carolina State University, invitations, correspondence with clients, and issues of forestry.
  - Gunnar Nicholson, 1963-1975 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Gunnar Nicholson, 1976-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Gunnar Nicholson, Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Gunnar Nicholson, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Gunnar Nicholson, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Gunnar Nicholson, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Gunnar Nicholson, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)